Guide to the James E. Jackson Audiotapes Collection OH.057
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- Series II: Lectures, Speeches
  - Peace Workshop, Milwaukee (2), Undated; cuid13901 (Cassette 228)
  - Peace Workshop, Milwaukee (3), Undated; cuid13902 (Cassette 229)
  - Side 1: Weinstock, L.: Trade Unione Movement, Bio - Dr. W.E.B. Du Bois; Side 2: Jackson, J.: Petty Burgeois Nationalism (1), Undated; cuid13903 (Cassette 230)
  - Petty Burgeois Nationalism (2), Undated; cuid13904 (Cassette 231)
  - Philosophy, Undated; cuid13905 (Cassette 232)
  - Side 1: Philosophy; Side 2: Historical Materialism, Undated; cuid13906 (Cassette 233)
  - Philosophy (2), Mar 1977; cuid13907 (Cassette 234)
  - Philosophy (3), Mar 1977; cuid13908 (Cassette 235)
  - Philosophy, Oct 1982; cuid13909 (Cassette 236)
  - Side 1: Philosophy; Side 2: Dialectical Materialism, Oct 1982; cuid13910 (Cassette 237)
  - Philosophy / Dialectical MaterialismNational School, Mar 1977; cuid13911 (Cassette 238)
  - Philosophy, Dialectics (4), Dec 1975; cuid13912 (Cassette 239)
  - Philosophical Falsifiers (2)AYD Reports, TM Report, Dec 1975; cuid13913 (Cassette 240)
  - Philosophical Falsifiers (3), Dec 1975; cuid13914 (Cassette 241)
  - Political Economy, Undated; cuid13915 (Cassette 242)
  - Political Economy, Undated; cuid13916 (Cassette 243)
  - Political Economy (3-4), Undated; cuid13917 (Cassette 244)
  - Side 1: Political Economy; Side 2: Inflation, Undated; cuid13918 (Cassette 245)
  - Side 1: Political Economy / Inflation; Side 2: Socialism, Undated; cuid13919 (Cassette 246)
  - Political Economy, Aug 1974; cuid13920 (Cassette 247)
  - Political Economy, Feb 1975; cuid13921 (Cassette 248)
  - Political Economy, Commodity ProductionLecture and Afterword Session, Feb 1975; cuid13922 (Cassette 249)
  - Side 1: Political Economy; Side 2: Accumulation of the Capital, Feb 1975; cuid13923 (Cassette 250)
  - Side 1: Lumer, Hy: Monetary Crisis; Side 2: Jackson, James: Political Economy Review (2), Dec 1975; cuid13924 (Cassette 251)
  - Political Economy, Jan 1976; cuid13925 (Cassette 252)
  - Side 1: Political Economy; Side 2: Questioning Students, Jan 1976; cuid13926 (Cassette 253)
  - Political Economy, Jan 1976; cuid13927 (Cassette 254)
  - Political Economy, Jul 1976; cuid13928 (Cassette 255)
  - Political Economy (1), Mar 1977; cuid13929 (Cassette 256)
  - Political Economy (2), Mar 1977; cuid13930 (Cassette 257)
  - Political Economy (3), Mar 1977; cuid13931 (Cassette 258)
  - Political Economy, Questions on (3), Mar 1977; cuid13932 (Cassette 259)
  - Political Economy, Aug 1977; cuid13933 (Cassette 260)
  - Political Economy, Jul 1978; cuid13934 (Cassette 261)
  - Political Economy (final), Jul 1978; cuid13935 (Cassette 262)
  - Politics and Revolution (2)National School, Mar 1977; cuid13936 (Cassette 263)
  - Portland, Maine Radio, Oct 1986; cuid13937 (Cassette 264)
  - Side 1: Principles of Party Organization and Functioning; Side 2: Industrial Concentration, Feb 1976; cuid13938 (Cassette 265)
  - Q&A On Children; Soviet Prophet, Undated; cuid13939 (Cassette 266)
  - Questions and Report from GRPS, Undated; cuid13940 (Cassette 267)
  - Questions for James E. Jackson, Undated; cuid13941 (Cassette 268)
  - Racism (5-6?), Undated; cuid13942 (Cassette 269)
  - Side 1: Racism; Side 2: Cont'd + Q&A's, Undated; cuid13943 (Cassette 270)
  - Racism, Fight Against, Undated; cuid13944 (Cassette 271)
  - Side 1: Racism with Mike Welch; Side 2: Party Organization with Mike Welch, Aug 1974; cuid13945 (Cassette 272)
  - Report back from Workshops (Jackson, J.; Meyers, G.), Undated; cuid13946 (Cassette 273)
  - Report on 60th Anniversary of Soviet Union, Dec 1977; cuid13947 (Cassette 274)
  - Report on Trip to China, Jul 1988; cuid13948 (Cassette 275)
  - Revolution Process / Components of Revolution, Aug 1977; cuid13949 (Cassette 276)
  - Revolutionary Conditions, Jan 1976; cuid13950 (Cassette 277)
  - School Evaluation (1), Feb 1976; cuid13951 (Cassette 278)
  - School Evaluation (2), Feb 1976; cuid13952 (Cassette 279)
  - School Graduation, Closing Speech, Mar 1975; cuid13953 (Cassette 280)
  - Situation of Black Americans, May 1979; cuid13954 (Cassette 281)
  - Social Economics 2/12, Undated; cuid13955 (Cassette 282)
  - Side 1: Social Revolution; Side 2: Discussion and Reports 2/28, Undated; cuid13956 (Cassette 283)
  - Side 1: Social Revolution; Side 2: Questions on Political Economy, Mar 1977; cuid13957 (Cassette 284)
  - Socialism, Undated; cuid13958 (Cassette 285)
  - Side 1: Socialism; Side 2: Lenin, the Party, Style in Leadership, Mar 1973; cuid13959 (Cassette 286)
  - On Socialism (3), May 1981; cuid13960 (Cassette 287)
  - On Socialism (4), May 1981; cuid13961 (Cassette 288)
  - Socialism and Communism (1), Undated; cuid13962 (Cassette 289)
  - Socialism and the Soviet Union, Aug 1979; cuid13963 (Cassette 290)
  - Socialist Convention / Unemployment (4), May 1979; cuid13964 (Cassette 291)
  - Socialist Revolution, Aug 1977; cuid13965 (Cassette 292)
  - Southern Negro Youth Congress Form (1), Undated; cuid13966 (Cassette 293, Box Digitized Access Files, File cuid13966)
    Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
    Format: 1/8" audiocassette, Duration: 60 min.
  - Southern Negro Youth Congress Form (2), Undated; cuid13967 (Cassette 294, Box Digitized Access Files, E-records cuid13967)
    Format: 1/8" audiocassette, Duration: 62 min.
  - Soviet Union, Undated; cuid13968 (Cassette 295)
  - Soviet Union, Aug 1974; cuid13969 (Cassette 296)
  - Soviet Union, Jul 1981; cuid13970 (Cassette 297)
  - On the Soviet Union Berlin Conference, Undated; cuid13971 (Cassette 298)
  - Staff Seminar Discussion, May 1979; cuid13972 (Cassette 299)
  - Side 1: The State; Side 2: Q&A, Undated; cuid13973 (Cassette 300)
  - The State, Feb 1975; cuid13974 (Cassette 301)
  - The State, Feb 1975; cuid13975 (Cassette 302)
  - Steel Strikes (?) and Socialism, Jul 1977; cuid13976 (Cassette 303)
  - Side 1: Strategy; Side 2: United Front, Tactics, Sectarianism with M. Welch, S. Douglas, Aug 1974; cuid13977 (Cassette 304)
  - Strategy and Tactics (2), Undated; cuid13978 (Cassette 305)
  - Side 1: Strategy and Tactics; Side 2: Irish Struggles, Mar 1977; cuid13979 (Cassette 306)
  - Strategy and Tactics, Aug 1977; cuid13980 (Cassette 307)
  - Strategy and Tactics with Gus Hall, Apr 1988; cuid13981 (Cassette 308)
  - Side 1: On Strategy and Tactics / Introduction of L. Dlugan; Side 2: Dlugan, Lee: Monopoly Prices and Profits, Imperialism / Historical, Jan 1976; cuid13982 (Cassette 309)
  - Suslov, In Memorial To, Undated; cuid13983 (Cassette 310)
  - Side 1: Theory of Knowledge; Side 2: Blank, Jan 1976; cuid13984 (Cassette 311)
  - Trade Union, Undated; cuid13985 (Cassette 312)
  - Side 1: Trade Union (White; Jackson, J.); Side 2: Woman Question(White; Jackson, J.), Undated; cuid13986 (Cassette 313)
  - Side 1: Trade Union; Side 2: National Question, Undated; cuid13987 (Cassette 314)
  - Trade Union Meeting or Conference, Undated; cuid13988 (Cassette 315)
  - Transition to Social Revolution and Left Center, Undated; cuid13989 (Cassette 316)
  - Trotsky, Undated; cuid13990 (Cassette 317)
  - Trotskyism, Undated; cuid13991 (Cassette 318)
  - United Front, Undated; cuid13992 (Cassette 319)
  - United Front (2-3), Undated; cuid13993 (Cassette 320)
  - United Front (3-4), Undated; cuid13994 (Cassette 321)
  - Side 1: United Front; Side 2: The YWLL (Young Workers' Liberation League), Undated; cuid13995 (Cassette 322)
  - Urgent Tasks in Fight for PeaceCentral Committee Report, Nov 1979; cuid13996 (Cassette 323)
  - VALB Socialist Scholars ConferenceWorkshop includes: Wellman, Saul, Apr 1994; cuid13997 (Cassette 324)
  - Washington, Feb 1980; cuid13998 (Cassette 325)
  - WBA I - J. Jackson with Bogdan Denitsch, Jan 1982; cuid13999 (Cassette 326)
  - W.E.B. Du Bois Memorial Lecture, Boston, Mar 1989; cuid14000 (Cassette 327)
  - W.E.B. Du Bois: Our Black Titan, Washington, D.C., Feb 1973; cuid14001 (Cassette 328)
  - West Berlin, Jan 1984; cuid14002 (Cassette 329)
  - Women's Equality (3-4), Undated; cuid14003 (Cassette 330)
  - Women's Question, Undated; cuid14004 (Cassette 331)
  - Women's Question (1) with J. Teixeira, Aug 1977; cuid14005 (Cassette 332)
  - Women's Question (2), Aug 1977; cuid14006 (Cassette 333)
  - Women's Question (3), Aug 1977; cuid14007 (Cassette 334)
  - Working Class History of the Nationalities Wheel (?)22nd Convention, Aug 1979; cuid14008 (Cassette 335)
  - World Peace CouncilMedal Ceremony for J. Jackson, Undated; cuid14009 (Cassette 336)
- Series III: Speeches by Others
  - Bert, Erik: Communist International, Undated; cuid14010 (Cassette 337)
  - Brodine, M. J.: Asians in America, Feb 1977; cuid14011 (Cassette 338)
  - Chandra, Romesh: World Peace Council, Jan 1978; cuid14012 (Cassette 339)
  - Dennis, Ellen with O. Harrington, P. Miriam: Berlin, Nov 1989; cuid14013 (Cassette 340)
  - Diskin, Louis and Others, Undated; cuid14014 (Cassette 341)
  - Fitzgerald, Albert: About Himself and about the Unions, Undated; cuid14015 (Cassette 342)
  - Hall, Gus: Side 1: PA Political Union; Side 2: Boston Conference, Nov 1981; cuid14016 (Cassette 343)
  - Hall, Gus: Main Address, N.C., Jan 1989; cuid14017 (Cassette 344)
  - Hall, Gus: On Greece + Q&A's, Undated; cuid14018 (Cassette 345)
  - Hall, Gus: Update, Aug 1988; cuid14019 (Cassette 346)
  - Hall, Gus: Update, Nov 1988; cuid14020 (Cassette 347)
  - Hall, Gus: Update, Jan 1989; cuid14021 (Cassette 348)
  - Hall, Gus: Update, Feb 1989; cuid14022 (Cassette 349)
  - Side 1: Hall, Gus Update; Side 2: J. Jackson, Jul 1990; cuid14023 (Cassette 350)
  - Hudson, Hosea, Undated; cuid14024 (Cassette 351)
  - Lipschutz, Joan; Jacques, Jeff, Aug 1977; cuid14025 (Cassette 352)
  - Mobhito, Moses: General Secretary, C.P. South Africa, Mar 28, 1968 (?); cuid14026 (Cassette 353)
  - Mobhito, Moses; Mullens, Leith; Diskin, Louis, Undated; cuid14027 (Cassette 354)
  - Side 1: Mora, Grace; Side 2: Winston, Henry, Skit of Students, Mar 1975; cuid14028 (Cassette 355)
  - Patrinos, Sandy: Strategy and Tactics: Party School, Mar 1975; cuid14029 (Cassette 356)
  - Shelby: Female Conflicts, Undated; cuid14030 (Cassette 357)
  - Smith, Betty: Party Theory (2), Mar 1975; cuid14031 (Cassette 358)
  - Smith, Betty: Party Theory (3), Mar 1975; cuid14032 (Cassette 359)
  - Side 1: Storey, Rasheed / Afternoon Plenary; Side 2: Afternoon Plenary, Undated; cuid14033 (Cassette 360)
  - Tyner, Jarvis: Political Report, Mar 1987; cuid14034 (Cassette 361)
  - Winston, Henry: Communist Party, Dec 1975; cuid14035 (Cassette 362)
  - Winston, Henry: School Opening, Feb 1978; cuid14036 (Cassette 363)
  - Winston, Henry Speech (3), Mar 1975; cuid14037 (Cassette 364)
  - Winston, Henry: Party Theory (3), Party School, Mar 1975; cuid14038 (Cassette 365)
  - Unknown Speaker (man): Class Struggle, Undated; cuid14039 (Cassette 366)
  - Unknown Speaker (man)Communist Unity, Undated; cuid14040 (Cassette 367)
  - Unknown Speaker(s): Discussion on an event at Carnegie Hall, Undated; cuid14041 (Cassette 368)
  - Unknown speaker (woman): Labor Union and the Party, Undated; cuid14042 (Cassette 369)
  - Unknown speaker (woman): Martin Luther King, Undated; cuid14043 (Cassette 370)
  - Unknown speakers: Political Economy - Student Session, Undated; cuid14044 (Cassette 371)
  - Unknown speakers: Students' Discussions and Presentations on Capitalism, Undated; cuid14045 (Cassette 372)
- Series IV: 7 inch reel of 1/4 inch-wide Recording Tapes
  - Patsu, Kofi and other unknown speakers: Young Farmers Rally at Kunnasi Chance, Mar 1965; cuid14046 (Cassette 373)